# Rajesh Sethi

## Software Engineer

3+ years of industry experience in product and platform development. Skilled in GO lang, Java, javascript, OOPs, AWS. Very good understanding of Concurrency, Scalability, Data structures, Algorithms, Database concepts and Operating system. Ability to learn new concepts and to adapt to new environments

rajeshsethi.56@gmail.com

Chennai, India

in linkedin.com/in/setraj

github.com/setraj

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# FreshWorks (formerly Freshdesk)

Team: Real Time Platforms

09/2018 - Present

Responsibilities: Backend engineer

- 1) Job Scheduler :: worked on scheduler service which is used by various products in the company to schedule job at some point in the future, on a recurring schedule or run jobs right away.
- tech stack: Go lang, RabbitMq, Kafka, Mysql, DynamoDb, stasD, Telegrapf, InfluxDB, Grafana, AWS
- 2) Service Monitoring Framework :: developed service which monitors the performance and uptime of any REST or WebSocket API
- It has features like Response checkers, HTTP Trace logs for failed requests, Average response time of each API endpoint, Embeddable NewRelic charts and lot more
- Responsible for end to end development process (development, testing, deployment).
- tech stack: Go lang, NewRelic, AWS

#### **SAP Labs India**

## Team: Public Services and Utility

10/2016 - 08/2018

Responsibilities: Backend Developer

- 1) Connection Discovery :: this application offers interactive visualizations to gain insights and explore connections in the form of graphs
- Worked on both UI and backend part of the application. Created UI components and developed backend services to fetch data from SAP HANA database.
- 2) Planograph :: this application offers grid view of a warehouse or any such storage place.
- Used "Overlapping rectangles Algorithm" to bring down the load time of the application.
- Techstack: Java, JavaScript, SAP ABAP, SAP HANA db

# Software Development Intern SAP Labs India

02/2016 - 07/2016

Responsibilities

- Developed an automation tool using C++ which significantly brought down the time taken by manual process.
- Involved in code debugging and fixing.

# **EDUCATION**

## **Master of Computer Applications** NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY - TRICHY

**SKILLS** 

Data Structures & Algorithms GO Lang **AWS** RabbitMa Kafka **Database Concepts** OOPS Docker Java os SQL

Concurrent Prgramming

## PERSONAL PROJECTS

#### CRITICAL RESOURCE MONITOR | Java

This application monitors a directory on a server where files are copied from multiple resources. This application keeps the size of the directory to a secured limit. It also handles removal of suspicious files from the directory.

#### INSIDE-OUT | A single player game | C++ □

- A game on the lines of Pac-man. The player has to obtain all the objects across all the six levels to win the game in given constraints. (No backtracking)
- https://setraj.github.io/gridgame

#### OOPs DICTIONARY | Java | Trie data structure

- This project is a menu-driven educative application for all fields of people for learning Object Oriented Programming Concepts. Implemented the Google Instant feature in the application.

## CODEONPAPER | JavaScript ✓

- A platform to prepare for personal Interviews where you are asked to write code on paper/whiteboard.
- https://setraj.github.io/codeonpaper/

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Runner Up in CodeBrunch (Codechef) coding competition 2015, ACM-NITT chapter
- Secured 3rd position in code competition at Vortex 2015 at Nit Trichy
- Runner Up in SAPTechnikal 2018 Table Tennis tournament at SAP Labs

### **INTERESTS**

**Problem Solving** 

**Distributed Systems** 

Cloud Computing

07/2013 - 07/2016 GPA: 7.78